Curriculum Vitae

Slawomir Tulski

Contact: Core language: Python

E-mail: slawomir.tulski@gmail.com Secondary languages: **JavaScript**, VBA,

Mobile: +44 7768098936 SQL, Bash, HTML5

GitHub: https://github.com/tulski-s

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/slawomir-tulski-091611116

Website: https://tulski-slawomir.herokuapp.com/

Personal summary:

I am a hardworking, passionate and imaginative Python programmer with one and half year of experience. I have an ability to work hard and smart, handle responsibilities and accomplish my assignments on time.

My recent commercial coding experience comes from my position as a Python Data Programmer at London start-up - Import.io. My main responsibilities were building python and java-script web-scrapers and contributing to python extraction framework. I also built two UIs: one was python's flask based web-application for managing team internal work. Second one was visual tool for building advanced configuration files for extraction framework mentioned earlier.

My other experience comes from my previous positions as a GIS Programmer and Python Teacher. I also use a lot of python while working scientifically, mainly with satellite data from NASA.

I spend my free time reading technical books and following tutorials on YouTube. When there is a chance, I like to attend workshops and meet-ups. Right now I would like to work a company where outstanding performance is recognized and where I can work on a complex long term projects. I would love to learn and gather as much experience as I can.

Career history:

SEP 2015 - FEB 2016, Import IO

Python Data Programmer

Tech: web-scrapping, Python, JavaScript, Selenium WebDriver, Linux, flask, bootstrap, html, node-red, regular expressions, xpaths.

At the beginning of my work my main tasks were building python and java-script web-scrapers and screening/formatting gathered data. To accomplish my goals I have used my problem-solving skills and creativity. Often I had to look for different work around to get data I wanted. Along with python and js I used vastly: regular expressions and Xpaths.

Soon I have got a new responsibilities, ie. contributing to python data extraction framework. I have written functions (and unit-tests for them) to make data extraction and cleaning simpler and more automated.

During my work I also built 2 UIs. First one was web-application (written in python's flask) for managing team internal work. The second one was visual tool for creating advanced configuration files for earlier-mentioned extraction framework. For later, I used node-red, which is node-js flow-based programming tool.

Curriculum Vitae

The idea of the 2nd UI appeared after I won (together with my coworker) one of company's hackathon. We presented there prototype of tool written in python and it's tkinter library. After that success, the project landed on the official product road-map.

JUL 2015, Grange Fencing Ltd

Tech: Python (numpy, tkinter, pyshp, PIL) and QGIS

Strategical analysis of optimal localization of company's warehouses in the territory of United Kingdom. I was responsible for transforming company's abstract calculation algorithm into computer application. I have used Python with pyshp and tkinter libraries. I have also created visual presentation of outcomes on digital maps (for this purpose I used open source GIS software – QGIS).

MAY 2015 - JUN 2015, Wroclaw University of Technology

Python Teacher/Lecturer

I was running classes and preparing materials for didactic purposes for future GIS specialists. Topics I have covered during my classes included Python language syntax, data types, creating custom functions, conditional statements, loops, writing more complex scripts, basics of OOP and ArcPy library. My goal was to give students a solid foundation for programming in Python and using ArcPy library for spatial analysis.

JAN 2015 - JUN 2015, Wroclaw Institute of Spatial Information and Artificial Intelligence

Assistant GIS Programmer/ GIS Programmer

Tech: Python (PIL, numpy), Windows batch scripting, QGIS/ArcGIS, SAGA-GIS, ImageStation

I was hired to develop algorithm for automate building detection from high resolution aerial images. It was a part of bigger application designed to improve property tax collecting system. Project was innovative because it utilizes the type of images usually not used for this purpose. To create appropriate solution I had to combine knowledge from remote sensing and image processing along with my own ideas. At the end, validation tests showed that my algorithm's detection rate was about 98%.

During my work I also wrote couple of python scripts to automate coworkers task and took part in other projects, eg. updating cities and addresses database or updating National Topographic Database. My role consisted mainly from data entering, but required also writing SQL gueries and data munging.

SEP 2015 - NOV 2015, Finnish Geodetic Institute

Intern

Tech: Python, Matlab

This internship was the result of my scientific research efforts that I made during my master's studies. I was responsible for terrestrial and mobile laser scanning field measurements and post-processing gathered data in specialized photometric software.

Curriculum Vitae

Education:

JUL 2014, Wroclaw University of Environmental and Life Science

Master's degree in the field of Geoinformatics

Course included modules on rational databases, SQL queries, programming with VBA (digital image processing, eg. transformations, filters and pixel-based calculations) and GIS programming.

I started my scientific projects on the use of ICESat satellite data to measure global tree heights and improving accuracy of SRTM digital elevation model (which is used inter alia by Google Earth)

I have gained the best possible score for my Master's thesis. I investigated there possibility of improving polish spatial database system with ICESat data.

FEB 2013, Wroclaw University of Environmental and Life Science Bachelor's degree in the field of Geodesy and Cartography

Publications:

Tulski S., Lidar in space (in Polish), Geodeta 2014, no. 5, pp. 15-17.

Tulski S., Improvement of Accuracy of the SRTM C-Band Digital Elevation Model Using the ICESat Ground Control Points. Poster presented at: ESA EO Summer School 2014, 4-14/08, Frascati, Italy

Wrokshops & Courses:

JAN 2016, White October Events

Advanced Javascript Workshop

The class gave me strong core understanding of the JS language and its execution model. It was driven by exercises and delivered me knowledge required to make effective use of JS on the back- or front-end. Some of included topics: scope, closures, functions, data structures, Combining OOP and functional programming.

AUG 2014, European Space Center, Frascati (Rome), Italy

Earth Observing Summer School

I was accepted as one of the youngest participants, because of my scientific achievements. Workshops included lectures and practical exercises about vastly understood Earth observing systems and basics of data assimilation and machine learning.